

Male, 30 years, born on 10 August 1994

Reside in: Almaty

Citizenship: Kazakhstan, work permit at: Kazakhstan

Ready to relocate: Austria, Almaty, Astana, Hungary, Germany, Georgia, Kyiv, China, Luxembourg, Minsk, Moscow, Poland, Saint Petersburg, Turkey, Finland, Croatia, Montenegro, Czech Republic, Switzerland, Sweden, ready for business trips

Desired position and salary

Frontend-разработчик

Specializations:

Programmer, developer

Employment: full time Work schedule: full day

Desired travel time to work: any

Work experience — 5 years 6 months

May 2022 — till now 2 years 7 months

BTS Digital

Astana, btsdigital.kz

IT, System Integration, Internet

• System Integration, Technological and Business Processes Automation, IT Consulting

Senior Web Developer

- * Working as a part of the team that is responsible for bringing music streaming service to the audience.
- * Building client faced UI interfaces using React and a mix of Material UI and custom built components.
- * Building internal admin portals using React/Remix in order to streamline and improve content management processes
- * Integrating code quality watchdogs via various linters and plugins
- * Daily meetings with the team to align on the status and direction our feature development processes
- * Participating in plannings and grooming to optimize feature development cycle
- * Supporting the QA team in feature testing

Main stack used: React, MobX, Craco, Material-UI, VideoJS, Remix, React-router v6.

November 2021

— May 2022
7 months

Inkitt

inkitt.com

IT, System Integration, Internet

• Internet Company (Search Engines, Payment Systems, Social Networks, Information and Educational, Entertainment Resources, Website Promotion etc.)

Remote React / React Native Developer

Working on high-load client side application as well as developing internal tools to simplify and streamline work process across various teams.

Using React.is, MobX-State-Tree, UI-Router as main frameworks to build internal tools.

Created an internal platform to manage campaigns and notification delivery system.

Worked on a content managing platform to allow authors edit, publish, and create immersive and static novels for users to consume worldwide.

Currently working on a React Native application that allows users to read and listen to novels created by authors around the world.

Main tech stack that I use daily:

- * React Native
- * MobX / MobX-State-Tree
- * Firebase
- * PostgreSQL
- * NestJS

July 2021 — November 2021 5 months

TargetAI

targetai.kz

IT, System Integration, Internet

Software Development

Frontend-разработчик

Integrating new features based on the business. Creating a front end of VA application and platform.

Working with React library.

Effector for state management.

Webpack for bundling.

Styled-Components for styling solution.

October 2020 — June 2021 9 months

Halyk Finservice (Halyk Bank)

Главный разработчик

Implementing new features on the web application using React, MobX, Webpack, Jenkins and Docker Constantly keeping track of the tasks that are done on back and front end

Participating in important business decisions when it comes to the overall look of the web application Checking in with the design team to make sure we are on track of our goals.

Conducting minor UX/UI surveys to further better the platform

Leading the new employees and interns

Constantly updating legacy code to be on top of any known vulnerabilities.

Conducting weekly meetups to determine any blockers or opportunities to improve.

June 2019 — September 2020 1 year 4 months

Camino Financial

Frontend-разработчик

Started as an intern back in mid-2019. After 2 months of extensive hands-on experience in React and GatsbyJS solidified my position as Front-End Web Developer. Was primarily responsible for form validations, animations, and implementing proposed UI. Worked closely with the design team to transform prototypes made in Xd, Figma, and Framer to React-based components. The latest project that our team tackled involved Vue, Nuxt, styled-components, and GSAP. Projects that I participated in involved styled-components, Framer-Motion, React, GatsbyJS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Express, Firebase, Node, and my personal favorite - GSAP.

Education

Bachelor

²⁰¹⁹ Thinkful

Web Development, Full Stack Web Developer

²⁰¹⁷ California State University, Northridge

Bachelor of Science, Marketing

2015 Los Angeles City College

Associate of Arts, Social and Behavioral Sciences

Tests, examinations

2020 HackingWithSwift.com

HackingWithSwift, iOS development using SwiftUI

Key skills

Languages Kazakh — Native

English — C2 — Proficiency Russian — C2 — Proficiency

Skills Code review Firebase ReactJS Gitlab Обучаемость React Node

React Native Express REST API CSS3 HTML5 JavaScript Git

Next.js Web Application Development Agile Project Management

FramerMotion Styled-Components Jenkins Docker Cypress NestJS

Ant.Design TailwindCSS Design System TypeScript MobX

Driving experience

Own car

Driver's license category B

Further information

About me

I am a web developer with many years of experience in customer-centric development. My goal is to create remarkable experiences online. I use MERN Stack as my main daily tool. Although lately, I am utilizing NextJs's capabilities in order to create a full fledge server side rendered applications. Additionally, my most recent place of work allows me to explore nits and picks of mobile development via React Native. Occasionally, I gravitate towards other languages such as Swift or Dart to create mobile applications. I am passionate about software development and anything that is related to the technology of our age.